Register of the Aleksandr Alekseevich Maslov papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Aleksandr Alekseevich Maslov papers
1908-1974
2011C2
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Correspondence, personal documents, and photographs, relating to Russian emigre affairs in China.
Maslov, Aleksandr Alekseevich.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2011.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Aleksandr Aleekseevich Maslov was a Russian White army officer. After the Russian revolution he fled Russia for China, later continuing on to live in the United States.
Scope and Content of Collection
These papers contain personal documents, photographs, and correspondence of White Army officer and Russian émigré Aleksandr Alekseevich Maslov. The papers reflect his personal life, commerce activities in China, and life as a Russian émigré. Additional materials in the Lommatsch family file document the lives of his relatives, and consist of correspondence and travel-related documents.
Russia--Emigration and immigration.; Russians--China.; Russians--United States.
- A. Maslov file, 1908-1950
  - Documents on Maslov's commercial activities in China, 1929-1948 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1953 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Photographs of A. Maslov, his family, and friends, 1908-1950 (Box-folder 1:3-6)
- Lommatsch family file, 1949-1974
  - Correspondence, 1946-1974
    - General, 1946-1953 (Box-folder 1:7-8)
    - Fetisoff, Sergei, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - Gertsvikh, M., 1953-1964 (Box-folder 1:10)
    - Hausoffer, F., 1950-1953 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - Holmberg, N., 1972-1974 (Box-folder 1:12-13)
    - Kalenichenko, N., 1961-1964 (Box-folder 1:14)
    - Kuper (Cooper), B., 1949-1950 (Box-folder 1:15)
    - Kuznetsov, E., 1950 (Box-folder 1:16)
    - Lavrentiev, A., 1971 (Box-folder 1:17)
    - Reyer, N., 1949-1964 (Box-folder 1:18)
  - International travel receipts, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 1:19)